<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to the #WAIQ Age</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Welcome to the #WAIQ Age</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 19:07:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Can an invention made with AI be patented?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/2025-11-10-can-an-invention-made-with-ai-be-patented/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 19:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/2025-11-10-can-an-invention-made-with-ai-be-patented/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The patent system has historically been one of the pillars of the innovation ecosystem: it offers an economic incentive to those who create; that is, there is the expectation of an economic benefit generated in exchange for the temporary transfer of the use of their inventions. But if part of the creative process is taken over by AI, how do we redefine the value, authorship, and protection of what has been invented?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation Super Hubs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/2025-11-10-innovation-super-hubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 19:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/2025-11-10-innovation-super-hubs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article explores the Global Innovation Index 2025, revealing how innovation is increasingly concentrated in specific &amp;ldquo;superhub&amp;rdquo; regions around the world. It highlights the rapid rise of Asian innovation powerhouses like Shenzhen–Hong Kong, Tokyo–Yokohama, Beijing, and Seoul, contrasted with traditional centers like Silicon Valley. The piece delves into the unique ecosystems that drive these clusters—combining cutting-edge research, industrial capacity, and dynamic financial networks—while emphasizing the critical role of state support and social networks in fueling innovation. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in understanding the future landscape of global technological leadership and the factors underpinning these high-impact innovation hubs, this article offers a compelling and insightful read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum IPO Landscape in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/2025-11-06-quantum-ipo-landscape-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 22:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/2025-11-06-quantum-ipo-landscape-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Investor interest in quantum stocks has surged as companies begin translating scientific breakthroughs into commercial products. Firms like Infleqtion and Xanadu exemplify this trend, leveraging public capital to accelerate development, broaden real-world applications, and pursue leadership in areas ranging from quantum sensing to next-generation processors.​&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This year is also notable for the diversity of quantum business models: while established players like IBM and Microsoft integrate quantum access into cloud platforms, newer pure plays focus on breakthrough hardware and scalable architectures. The capital influx from IPOs aims to position these companies for leadership in areas like AI acceleration, national security, photonic computing, and advanced cryptography.​&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spain Unveils the National Quantum Technology Strategy 2025-2030</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/2025-11-06-informe-cuantica/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 22:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/2025-11-06-informe-cuantica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is with great pride that we announce the official unveiling of Spain&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;National Quantum Technology Strategy 2025-2030&lt;/strong&gt;, a landmark roadmap that places Spain at the forefront of European and global quantum innovation. This comprehensive document is the outcome of a collaborative effort between the Ministry for Digital Transformation and Public Function and the Ministry of Science, Innovation and Universities. It marks a crucial step forward in propelling quantum technologies within the country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaleup Europe Fund launch: EU Commission accelerates investment in
advanced technologies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/2025-11-07-scaleup-europe-fund-launch-eu-commission-accelerates-investment-in-advanced-technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 19:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/2025-11-07-scaleup-europe-fund-launch-eu-commission-accelerates-investment-in-advanced-technologies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From EU News &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eunews.it/en/2025/10/28/scaleup-europe-fund-launch-eu-commission-accelerates-investment-in-advanced-technologies/&#34;&gt;https://www.eunews.it/en/2025/10/28/scaleup-europe-fund-launch-eu-commission-accelerates-investment-in-advanced-technologies/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI Grand Bargain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/2025-11-07-the-ai-grand-bargain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 20:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/2025-11-07-the-ai-grand-bargain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben Buchanan and Tantum Collins argues in Foreign Affairs for a new American model of artificial intelligence development based on a “grand bargain” between the tech industry and the government. This agreement would balance innovation with ethical oversight and security concerns. The authors emphasize the need for government involvement to regulate AI while incentivizing private sector investment and leadership.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WAIQ-complete use cases involving the three technologies </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/2023-11-28-waiq-complete-use-cases-involving-the-three-technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/2023-11-28-waiq-complete-use-cases-involving-the-three-technologies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, we consider some of the use cases of integrating quantum computing with artificial intelligence and web3 technologies, focusing on the technical aspects and challenges involved. We hope that they inspire and inform the experts and enthusiasts of these fields to pursue further exploration and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantum-finance&#34;&gt;Quantum finance&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the use case of applying quantum cloud, quantum machine learning, and quantum internet to enhance the efficiency and security of DeFi web3 services and applications, such as decentralized exchanges, lending platforms, stablecoins, and insurance. Quantum finance can enable faster and more accurate price discovery, risk analysis, portfolio optimization, and fraud detection, as well as more robust and scalable encryption, authentication, and verification. Some examples of quantum finance projects are Q2B, QC Ware, QuantFi, and QED-it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use Cases of Quantum Computing and Web3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/2023-11-28-use-cases-of-quantum-computing-and-web-3-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 23:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/2023-11-28-use-cases-of-quantum-computing-and-web-3-0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantum-decentralized-applications&#34;&gt;Quantum decentralized applications&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the application of quantum algorithms and hardware to create web3 applications that run on distributed quantum networks and protocols. Quantum decentralized applications can harness the quantum properties of coherence, entanglement, and superposition to enable more secure and robust functionality, such as quantum voting, quantum auctions, quantum games, and quantum social networks. Some examples of quantum decentralized applications are QVote, QubitDAO, and QubitBook.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantum-cryptography&#34;&gt;Quantum cryptography&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the application of quantum algorithms and hardware to enhance the security and privacy of web3 communications, transactions, and contracts. Quantum cryptography can exploit the quantum properties of no-cloning, uncertainty, and entanglement to enable key distribution, encryption, authentication, and verification that are immune to eavesdropping, tampering, and forgery by classical or quantum adversaries. Some examples of quantum cryptography protocols are quantum key distribution, quantum digital signatures, quantum secure direct communication, and quantum blind signatures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use Cases of Quantum Computing and Artificial Intelligence </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/2023-11-26-use-cases-of-quantum-computing-and-artificial-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 23:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/2023-11-26-use-cases-of-quantum-computing-and-artificial-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantum-machine-learning-platforms&#34;&gt;Quantum machine learning platforms&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the application of quantum algorithms and hardware to provide web3 with scalable and interoperable platforms for developing, deploying, and running quantum machine learning applications. Quantum machine learning platforms can leverage the quantum advantages of speedup, accuracy, and complexity to enable more efficient and effective data processing, feature engineering, model training, and inference. Some examples of quantum machine learning platforms are Qiskit Machine Learning, PennyLane, TensorFlow Quantum, and Amazon Braket.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patricia Ramos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/picture/2023-11-05-patricia-ramos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/picture/2023-11-05-patricia-ramos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IP expert&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#WAIQers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/banner/whoweare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/banner/whoweare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;#WAIQ&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; was born in July 2023 as a summer course at &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Harvard Law School&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. 3 days for revisiting 3 technologies from 3 relevant dimensions: technical, legal and ethical.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. Beyond the course, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;#WAIQ&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; is a forum where innovators, legal professionals and other curious minds shared knowledge, experiences, challenges, oportunities and concerns around #web3, #AI and #quantum.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Meet the #WAIQers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carlos Kuchkovsky</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/picture/ck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/picture/ck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quantum contributor&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esperanza Cuenca Gómez</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/picture/ecg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/picture/ecg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quantum contributor&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/banner/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/banner/home/</guid>
      <description>Today, every company naturally integrates its strategies around web,&#xA;mobile and cloud. It is inconceivable that they can be understood as separate&#xA;disciplines. In a few years, history will repeat itself with three other&#xA;disciplines: &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;web3&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, AI and quantum. All three will feed back&#xA;and complement each other and their convergence will multiply the&#xA;opportunities for startups and corporates to develop new competitive&#xA;advantages. Want to join us?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>José Luis Amat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/picture/jlar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/picture/jlar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founder &amp;amp; Web3 lawyer&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>José Luis Núñez</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/picture/jln/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/picture/jln/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lecturer &amp;amp; Web3 contributor&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luis Ignacio Vicente</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/picture/livdo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/picture/livdo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founder &amp;amp; Ideologist&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ricardo Vidal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/picture/rv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/picture/rv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quantum &amp;amp; Innovator&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upsss!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/banner/404/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/banner/404/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/elements/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whoops! Page not found</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/404/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/404/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That page can&amp;rsquo;t be found.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our latest content is &lt;a href=&#34;./&#34;&gt;on the homepage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
