<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to #WAIQ Age</title>
    <link>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Welcome to #WAIQ Age</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 22:40:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://waiq-full.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quantum IPO Landscape in 2025</title>
      <link>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/article/2025-11-06-quantum-ipo-landscape-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 22:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/article/2025-11-06-quantum-ipo-landscape-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>Investor interest in quantum stocks has surged as companies begin translating scientific breakthroughs into commercial products. Firms like Infleqtion and Xanadu exemplify this trend, leveraging public capital to accelerate development, broaden real-world applications, and pursue leadership in areas ranging from quantum sensing to next-generation processors.​
This year is also notable for the diversity of quantum business models: while established players like IBM and Microsoft integrate quantum access into cloud platforms, newer pure plays focus on breakthrough hardware and scalable architectures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAIQ-complete use cases involving the three technologies </title>
      <link>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/article/2023-11-28-waiq-complete-use-cases-involving-the-three-technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/article/2023-11-28-waiq-complete-use-cases-involving-the-three-technologies/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we consider some of the use cases of integrating quantum computing with artificial intelligence and web3 technologies, focusing on the technical aspects and challenges involved. We hope that they inspire and inform the experts and enthusiasts of these fields to pursue further exploration and innovation.
Quantum finance This is the use case of applying quantum cloud, quantum machine learning, and quantum internet to enhance the efficiency and security of DeFi web3 services and applications, such as decentralized exchanges, lending platforms, stablecoins, and insurance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Cases of Quantum Computing and Web3</title>
      <link>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/article/2023-11-28-use-cases-of-quantum-computing-and-web-3-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 23:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/article/2023-11-28-use-cases-of-quantum-computing-and-web-3-0/</guid>
      <description>Quantum decentralized applications This is the application of quantum algorithms and hardware to create web3 applications that run on distributed quantum networks and protocols. Quantum decentralized applications can harness the quantum properties of coherence, entanglement, and superposition to enable more secure and robust functionality, such as quantum voting, quantum auctions, quantum games, and quantum social networks. Some examples of quantum decentralized applications are QVote, QubitDAO, and QubitBook.
Quantum cryptography This is the application of quantum algorithms and hardware to enhance the security and privacy of web3 communications, transactions, and contracts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Cases of Quantum Computing and Artificial Intelligence </title>
      <link>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/article/2023-11-26-use-cases-of-quantum-computing-and-artificial-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 23:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/article/2023-11-26-use-cases-of-quantum-computing-and-artificial-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>Quantum machine learning platforms This is the application of quantum algorithms and hardware to provide web3 with scalable and interoperable platforms for developing, deploying, and running quantum machine learning applications. Quantum machine learning platforms can leverage the quantum advantages of speedup, accuracy, and complexity to enable more efficient and effective data processing, feature engineering, model training, and inference. Some examples of quantum machine learning platforms are Qiskit Machine Learning, PennyLane, TensorFlow Quantum, and Amazon Braket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patricia Ramos</title>
      <link>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/picture/2023-11-05-patricia-ramos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/picture/2023-11-05-patricia-ramos/</guid>
      <description>IP expert</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#WAIQers</title>
      <link>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/banner/whoweare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/banner/whoweare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;#WAIQ&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; was born in July 2023 as a summer course at &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Harvard Law School&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. 3 days for revisiting 3 technologies from 3 relevant dimensions: technical, legal and ethical.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. Beyond the course, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;#WAIQ&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; is a forum where innovators, legal professionals and other curious minds shared knowledge, experiences, challenges, oportunities and concerns around #web3, #AI and #quantum.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Meet the #WAIQers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carlos Kuchkovsky</title>
      <link>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/picture/ck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/picture/ck/</guid>
      <description>Quantum contributor</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Esperanza Cuenca Gómez</title>
      <link>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/picture/ecg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/picture/ecg/</guid>
      <description>Quantum contributor</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/banner/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/banner/home/</guid>
      <description>Today, every company naturally integrates its strategies around web, mobile and cloud. It is inconceivable that they can be understood as separate disciplines. In a few years, history will repeat itself with three other disciplines: &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;web3&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, AI and quantum. All three will feed back and complement each other and their convergence will multiply the opportunities for startups and corporates to develop new competitive advantages. Want to join us?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>José Luis Amat</title>
      <link>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/picture/jlar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/picture/jlar/</guid>
      <description>Founder &amp;amp; Web3 lawyer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>José Luis Núñez</title>
      <link>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/picture/jln/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/picture/jln/</guid>
      <description>Lecturer &amp;amp; Web3 contributor</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luis Ignacio Vicente</title>
      <link>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/picture/livdo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/picture/livdo/</guid>
      <description>Founder &amp;amp; Ideologist</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ricardo Vidal</title>
      <link>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/picture/rv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/picture/rv/</guid>
      <description>Quantum &amp;amp; Innovator</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upsss!</title>
      <link>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/banner/404/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/banner/404/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whoops! Page not found</title>
      <link>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/404/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waiq-full.netlify.app/404/</guid>
      <description>That page can&amp;rsquo;t be found.
Our latest content is on the homepage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
